Look at your neighbor. Tell your
neighbor, "You're looking good."
>> You're looking good.
>> Better than yesterday.
>> And tomorrow.
>> This week.
>> You will shine.
>> In Jesus name.
>> Meta. Meta
>> meta meta
>> sparkle sparkle
>> sparkle sparkle.
>> Shiny shiny
>> shiny shiny
shades.
>> Wear shades if you have. Come on, let's
give God a big hand.
While we are standing, we want to read
the word for today.
This is a new month and God has been
gracious to bring us into this new
month. Why don't we just thank him and
just bless him for that?
We've been talking about vision,
open door vision. This month we are
talking about open door declarations
and as we see we also want to say. So as
we see we also want
>> to say this passage
gives us a glimpse of how Jesus spoke
into the situations of life. It starts
with verse 12. I read from verse 12 to
14 and then I will jump to verse 20.
The next day as they were leaving
Bethany, Jesus was hungry. Seeing in the
distance a fig tree in leaf, he went to
find out if it had any fruit. When he
reached it, he found nothing but leaves.
because it was not the season for figs.
Then he said to the tree, he said to the
tree, uh, he said to the tree,
>> I'm saying that he said to the tree,
>> "May no one ever eat fruit from you
again." And it was loud enough because
his disciples
heard him say.
>> Then verse 20, in the morning as they
went along, they saw the fig tree
[clears throat] withered from the roots.
And Peter remembered and said to Jesus,
"Rabbi, look, the fig tree you cast has
withered." And Jesus said, "Have faith
in God." Jesus answered, "Truly I tell
you, if anyone
says, if anyone
>> says, if anyone
>> says to this mountain, go throw yourself
into the sea and does not doubt in their
heart, but believes that what they say
will happen, it will be done for them.
Therefore, I tell you, whatever you ask
for in prayer, believe that you have
received it, not that you will receive
it. Believe that
>> you have received it and it will be
yours.
>> This is God's word. God's people say,
>> "Amen."
>> Amen. Thank you. Be seated in God's
presence. those watching us online,
Karibusana,
those in the pavilion and other spaces.
God bless you as we receive his word.
Let's pray. Father, the Bible says that
faith comes by hearing and hearing the
word of God. And so we thank you and we
honor you for that. As this man of God
speaks, may this word become alive
and clear, encouraging and upholding,
releasing and establishing the purposes
of God on the earth today
because we have prayed in Jesus name and
gospel said,
>> "Amen."
>> Amen.
Are [clears throat] you glad to be in
God's house? Yes,
>> this month we talk about words
because declarations
are words.
We thank God for what God does in this
church and I want to read two
testimonies that have come our way and
we just want to celebrate with these
ones who who shared them.
This member writes and says, "I would
like to say a big thank you uh to pastor
Ambrose and the entire community.
Last year, Pi passi pi
asked that we write and lift up our
seven things
and all my seven have come to pass."
Amen.
And then she adds and says all
all not one but all seven of them.
I came back to say thank you and to
bless the Lord. God is good all the
time. I always tune in online.
Hallelujah. Amen.
>> I always tune in online on Sundays and
wherever I am in the country, I do come
to the 11 service and the worship team
is always so amazing.
Amen.
So that's a member, an online member. We
thank God.
Last Sunday I was talking about a lady
who sent a testimony concerning
uh anointing service that God
[clears throat] blessed her and she
wrote quite a bit but I want to pick her
story from the middle. Uh she was
pregnant and she had a challenge with
that pregnancy. She was also unwell. She
caught COVID in the process and just
many things were happening to her. But
God is a good God. So I picked the story
uh in the middle
[clears throat] when she suddenly was in
the office and she felt herself wet. The
B she says, "I called a few people as I
somehow suspected my water had broken
and upon getting home the leak became so
heavy we had to rush to the nearest
hospital. Long story short, the doctor
confirmed it was the amniotic fluid and
he suggested immediate surgery to
deliver the baby since according to him
the baby was at risk. In tears, I called
my gyne and she made an immediate
arrangement for me to be admitted at
Aakhan Aakhan maternity. I would end up
testing positive for COVID uh 19 and was
classified as a high-risisk patient
because of the compromised pregnancy.
They took precautions and administered
injections to mature the baby's lungs in
case I go into labor. I was so scared.
Would my child be okay? Would she make
it? Will there be complications? Will I
be in hospital for months waiting for
the child to be discharged? But I
strengthened myself in the Lord. My
family went into prayer mode and we
really pray. At this point, I had been
moved to the isolation ward with only my
husband allowed to visit. I decided I
was not going to miss the anointing
service and I joined online.
I could feel the Holy Spirit in that
room. [clears throat] I was in an
isolated room, but I was not alone. I
sensed the move of God from when the
worship session began.
By the time Pastor Ambrose came to the
stage, I was as ready for a miracle. I
did not have my anointing oil. I I did
not have my anointing oil.
But I had my body lotion.
Thank you, Jesus.
I had my body lotion with me. And that
is what pastor Ambrose prayed for. Uh
for some reason that day, Pastor Ambrose
prayed a lot for children. And he
particularly said that our children are
for signs and wonders. A declaration I
adopted through the remaining period. As
I was anointing my belly, my baby girl
was so active in the womb for me was
confirmation enough that God had done
it. I would later let her be discharged
and told the following things.
[clears throat] The best doctors would
do the best doctors would do uh is try
to hold the pregnancy for at most up to
34 weeks. The baby was currently at 30
weeks.
There were many risks of the baby
getting infected since the water that
protects the child had leaked. I needed
to pay attention to my vitals and rush
to hospital in case I sensed fevers. My
lotion became my anointing oil and I
would make Pastor Ambrose's declarations
as I rubbed my belly every day. The
things that people do.
Hello. My testimony. My baby made it up
to 37 weeks.
and was safely delivered via CS. Given
the history with a pregnancy, my water
stopped leaking after 5 days and God
restored the water volume in the uterus.
It was always nor it was always normal
volume. I did scans every week after 30
weeks and worked closely with my gyne.
My doctor confirmed that this is what
they call a medical miracle. This case
was a very unique one that marvel
doctors. My baby girl is now 10 months.
Thank you, Jesus.
Amen.
And she's our pride and her and and joy.
Her milestones amaze us. She has already
learned to walk at 10 months.
Let's celebrate Jesus Christ.
And then she finished there by saying,
uh, I'm looking forward to today's
service and I know I will see God. Uh,
God is a good God.
>> Isn't God good?
>> I thought it needful to read those
testimonies because we have many
testimonies. Sometimes we don't get the
privilege of hearing them because
they're here and God is a God of signs
and wonders. And as we preach,
as Pastor Simo prays, God shifts things.
God moves situations. And this month, as
we talk about open door declarations, be
be guided that what you say is very
important.
Hallelujah.
So Jesus said this. So let me repeat
those words. He said in Mark 11 verse
20- 23,
the disciples have heard an object
lesson that you can speak to something
and and it listens to you. You can speak
to a tree and things changed. You can
speak to your vehicle that has told and
things can shift. Hello. You can speak
to a child and things just change.
And he said this in the morning as they
went along
they saw the fig tree withered from the
roots. Peter remembered and said to
Jesus, "Rabbi,
look, the fig tree you cast has
withered." And Jesus was basically
saying, "I knew it would happen. That
should not surprise you." And Jesus
said, "I'm I was doing that for you."
Then he says this,
"Have faith
in God. believe that God can use your
declarations to shift a situation. Then
he said, "Truly I tell you, if anyone
says to this mountain," now from a fig
tree to a mountain, a fig tree is a
small thing. A mountain is a big thing.
He's saying you can even say to a
something that is so difficult.
If anyone says to this mountain,
this hindrance,
go throw yourself into the sea, and does
not doubt in their heart, but believes
that what they say will happen, it will
be done for them.
What you say is very important. Tell
your neighbor, your tongue is very
powerful.
>> Your tongue is very powerful. Let me
read that verse in Proverbs 18:21.
Proverbs 18:21
says the following about the tongue.
The tongue has the power of life and
death and those who love it will eat its
fruit. Let me read it in the New King
James version.
New King James says it this way. Death
and life are in the power of the tongue
and those who love it will eat its
fruit.
And in the first service I was telling
them I don't know why this verse uh is
close to the next verse. You know
sometimes you check a verse which is
close to another verse. So this one is
the one that is closest. I don't know
what that means.
Hello.
He who
>> finds a wife finds
>> a good thing and obtains
>> favor from the Lord. I don't know it's
because that a man has to speak first uh
before he finds a wife. Hello. But
that's a good verse. Uh for some of us
uh you can catch it. I know Pastor Simon
was uh announcing about two of our
members. One of them is Pastor Maxi.
Tell your neighbor amen.
>> Amen. Uh they found
um so he who finds he who finds he who
finds and that's important because it is
he who should find uh he's the one who
should find ladies you should not go
around trying to find.
You need to be found.
>> Oh thank you Jesus. Uh did you hear the
men saying amen?
And the ladies are sitting there saying
they are not finding us. H they are not
finding us. They need to find us. Uh he
who finds a wife finds a good thing and
not again he who finds a wife not he who
finds a girlfriend.
Uh because
you have a man has to reach a stage when
he's not no longer looking for
girlfriends.
Thank you Jesus. He needs to now say
Lord I need
>> a wife and I pray that ladies who are
single that you are a wife material.
I'm saying you're a wife material.
>> Thank you, Jesus. I'm especially
encouraging the men uh the men the men
because the ladies are already ready.
They are waiting to be found.
They're waiting to be found. So, men
rise to the occasion and find them.
Don't don't worry that you don't have a
job. God is good. Uh but you better find
a job. Uh because it's it's also
important that you find a job because in
the book of Genesis, the Bible says that
before Eve came, Abraham was working.
Adam, Adam was working. He was working.
While he was working, God said, "It is
not good
for the man to be alone. I'll make for
him."
Thank you, Jesus. Uh, I don't know why
I'm saying that, but may somebody
receive it
>> in Jesus name.
>> God is good.
>> And so we thank God. We thank God for
the opportunities that are coming our
way. But but words are important. And I
want to break it down to three
statements. Number one,
this month as we decree and declare, we
need to remember that words. God is
going to give us words that create.
Number two, he's going to give us words
that authorize and he's going to give us
words that bless.
Human beings are relational beings, but
they also conversational beings. We not
only relate with one another, we also
converse with one another. We talk to
one another. Animals talk in a different
way. Birds talk in a different way. But
God has given us speech so that we can
talk to one another. We are relational
and that is why we come to church
because some of us come to church not
just not even just to listen to the
message but to meet people.
Hello. We meet people. Can you imagine
coming to church and then there's nobody
here? Nobody. You know you you'll just
walk out and go back home because you
like to meet people. You want to find
out the your friends. You want to find
out the new fashion trends that that are
around. Uh tell your neighbor, "Amen."
>> Amen.
>> Yes. You want to know what is happening
around. So you like to meet we are
relational.
But in relating we also want to talk to
one another. We want to speak to one
another. God is like that. God is
relational. And so God not only wants to
talk to you, God wants you to talk to
him. God loves to be talked to. And and
even when you don't have anything to
tell God, just talk to him. Just tell
God, you're amazing. You're wonderful.
You're glorious. And God, I don't have
enough vocabulary, but let me tell you
this. This this day you have created is
just perfect. Talk to him because God
wants to talk to you. We are relational
beings. And in relating, we relate with
words. We speak with words. We start
with God himself in Genesis chapter one.
He spoke and the Bible says this because
words create. Genesis chapter one, in
the beginning, [clears throat] God
created the heavens and the earth. Now
the earth was formless and empty.
Darkness was over the surface of the
deep and the spirit of God was hovering
over the waters. And then God did what?
>> God did what?
>> He said, he spoke. God declared
something and he said, "Let there be
light." He did not discuss the
formlessness.
He did not discuss the darkness. He did
not analyze the very difficult challenge
before him. He simply declared, he spoke
into that situation. And the Bible says,
he said, "Let there be light." And there
was light. Verse four, God saw that the
light was good [clears throat] and he
separated the light from the darkness.
God called the light day and the
darkness he called night and there was
evening and there was morning, the first
day. From day one, God was speaking and
God now was creating people who' now
speak. And God wants us to decree. God
wants us to declare. Not only does God
want us to see, God also wants us to
decree and declare and say because God
is a good God. Amen.
>> I want you to know that when God speaks,
he says, "Let there be light. Let there
be wealth. Let there be life." And God
is saying for us, if you're going to
speak something good in a day, declare,
"Let there be light. Let there be
wealth. Let there be life.
Our words
advance the kingdom of God.
Our words advance the kingdom of God.
Our words can bring good. Our words can
bring evil. Our words can direct a
situation or misdirect a situation.
We grow in in in knowing how to talk and
how how how we engage one another. It is
a learning experience.
Um, when I was about to get married, I
was dating Martha. Tell your neighbor,
"Amen."
>> Amen.
>> Now, I was a pastor dating a congregant.
Tell your neighbor, "Amen."
>> Amen.
>> Because basically, I was in church
most of my life. always in church.
Anyway, got married, got got was dating
Martha [clears throat]
and I was still learning how to talk,
how to communicate.
So, we went for somebody's birthday and
some of our friends we went for a
birthday and in that birthday we were
introducing one another one by one. Each
person was introducing themselves.
So, this person introduced introduced
them. They came to me and I introduced
myself and I said, "My name is Pastor
Ambrose and I thank God that I'm saved
and I'm glad to be in this birthday."
And I sat down.
Martha, who was next to me, stood up.
She said, "I'm Martha Hassandi and I'm
glad to be in this birthday." She sat
down.
But in sitting down,
her mood changed.
And you know when a lady's moods change
the atmosphere around changes
things just become cold.
So we are walking home she's not talking
to me
and her face is just looking like I've
done something wrong. And me being a
man,
I cannot discern
what just happened. You see, no wonder
the Bible says it is not good for man to
be
>> alone. There are things he does not need
quickly.
So later we are talking I'm asking her
mother what is wrong? She said you did
not introduce me.
But I said people were asked to
introduce themselves one by one.
How could I know that? After introducing
myself, I needed to introduce you.
She said, "But you're the one who took
me to the birthday.
You needed to tell them why you are with
this person." I I found that difficult
to understand.
So, she needed me to I introduce myself.
I say I'm pastor Ambrose Yango, senior
pastor of Parkland's Baptist Church and
today it is my pleasure that I've come
with Martha
who is fill in the blanks
and that would just make her day.
I didn't know that. Now I'm talking to
the men who are in the house. Please
learn from me. learn learn from me learn
from my experience
that even though she I would introduce
her she would also even stand up and
still introduce herself but she'd be
very excited that now in the midst of
all these people they know thank you
Jesus they know they know they know they
know
when we got married I still was still
learning to know how to engage her to
talk to her
because words are powerful
So one day I'm driving her. I'm dropping
her at Nairobi hospital cuz she was
working there in the admin department.
So we are driving and while we are going
she's talking to me and then she says by
the way Ambrose
um I need money for food for evening.
Now I'm taking her to work.
Hello. She's going
>> to work.
That means she earns
>> money.
We're going to work.
So in that early those early years of
marriage which are can be very
challenging,
I made a statement
and I said it in Swahili but let me say
it in English. I said to her, "Your
money is finished."
Even though the heater in the car was
there, it became suddenly cold
at that time. Even I I don't know. I
didn't know I had made that mistake. I
did. I had no idea.
She stopped talking to me. When I
reached Narobi Hospital, she opened the
door and continued walking as she went.
I had to walk out and close the door.
I'm wondering what have I done?
So later in the evening, she comes home.
She makes supper. She's not talking to
me.
She serves the food. She's not talking
to me. And suddenly I realize Nikubai
Then I must as slowly she begins to talk
and she says why did you say that? Now
can you imagine those are the her first
one. Why did you say that? Now what do I
I've been talking the whole day.
So she's her conversation is continuing
from
the vehicle.
All the things we go through I'm telling
you.
But you have to learn these things. And
suddenly I realized I had made a serious
blunder
and I said, "Ma, I'm sorry. I was I was
you know in you say
I was not saying it badly
or in a bad way. And from that day I
told myself,
my money
is M's money.
And Martha's money
>> is her money
and no questions asked
>> whether she still has it
>> or not.
>> I'm telling you, tell your neighbor,
foolishness out,
>> foolishness out,
>> wisdom in,
>> wisdom in. And for me that day wisdom
came in
and it is still with me. I've never
asked that question. Of course later she
finished uh she she she left Nairobi
hospital. Um she went into catering and
she's in her businesses. But I tell
myself what whenever she asks for money
I'll give her money. If I don't have it
I will look for it. Thank you Jesus.
Amen.
And no wonder God has enabled us to live
this long. Uh and uh this this year this
this year, yeah, we shall be celebrating
30 years.
>> Uh
in our marriage. Uh but I had to learn
how to talk. Tell your neighbor, you
need to learn how to talk.
>> You need to learn how to talk
>> in Jesus name.
>> In Jesus name.
>> Wisdom is very important. And so as we
talk and speak, words that create, they
must be spoken from a place of wisdom.
Solomon experienced this. First Kings
chapter 3 verse 5. This was Solomon when
he first came as a king. The Bible says
at Gibon,
the Lord appeared to Solomon during the
night in a dream and God said, "Ask for
whatever you want me to give you."
Solomon answered, "You have shown great
kindness to your servant, my father
David, because he was faithful to you
and righteous and upright in heart, you
have continued this great kindness to
him, and have given him a son to sit on
his throne this very day." Now, Lord, my
God, you have made your servant king in
place of my father David, but I'm only a
little child and do not know how to
carry out my duties. Your servant is
here among the people. You have chosen a
great people too numerous to count on
number. So give your servant a
discerning heart to govern your people
and to distinguish between right and
wrong. For who is able to govern this
great people of yours?
The Lord was pleased that Solomon had
asked for this. So God said to him,
"Since you have asked for this, are not
for long life or wealth for yourself,
nor have asked for the death of your
enemies, but for discernment in
administering justice, I will do what
you have asked. I will give you a wise
and a discerning heart so that there
will never So go back. So that there
will never have been anyone like you."
nor will there ever be. Moreover, I will
give you what you have not asked for,
both wealth and honor, so that in your
lifetime you will have no equal among
kings. Tell your neighbor, wisdom.
>> Wisdom.
>> And I'm telling you, we need wisdom. The
Bible says this in James 3:17, again
talking about the tongue and talking
about wisdom, it says this, "But the
wisdom that comes from heaven is first
of all pure, then peaceloving,
considerate,
submissive, full of mercy and good
fruit, impartial and sincere.
peacemakers who sow in peace reap a
harvest of righteousness.
Solomon himself said in Proverbs chapter
4 verse 7 again talking about wisdom
because it is wisdom that creates. He
said this the beginning of wisdom is
this.
Let me say that again. Proverbs 4:7. The
beginning of wisdom is this. Get wisdom
though it does what?
It costs all you have. Get
understanding. It says the next verse,
cherish her. In other words, cherish
wisdom and she will do what?
>> Exalt you. Embrace wisdom and she will
>> honor you. Wisdom will give you a
gallant to grace your head and present
you with a glorious crown. Wisdom is
important.
Go to Proverbs 24:3
again. It says, "This wisdom that
creates," he says this, "By wisdom a
house
>> is built, and through understanding it
is established. Through knowledge, its
rooms are filled with rare and beautiful
treasures." Verse five, the wise prevail
through great power, and those who have
knowledge master their strength. Surely
verse six, you need guidance to wage war
and victory is won through many
advisor. Wisdom is too high for fools.
In the assembly of the gate, they must
not open their mouths. Hello.
>> Wisdom is important. Tell your neighbor,
wisdom.
>> Wisdom.
>> And I'm telling you that wisdom creates.
Wisdom makes things happen. And so
pastor Simon this month we are decreeing
and declaring let there be light.
>> We are saying into dark situations let
there be light.
>> We are saying into situation that has
the scarcity let there be light. Let the
the wisdom of light come to you in Jesus
name.
>> Light travels from the sun to the earth
at a speed of 186,000
miles per second.
The sun is about 93 million miles from
the earth. And so if you calculate that
distance, light takes 8 minutes to come
from the sun to where you are. The
moment we say let there be light, our
words are at a speed of light 186,000
miles a second.
So when we speak, things change. When we
declare, things shift. The Bible says in
Job 22 28, I'm reading from the New King
James Version here, and it says this,
uh, you will also declare a thing and it
will be established for you. And then he
says, so light will shine on your ways.
That light is wisdom. That light is the
power of God to create. When God said,
"Let there be light," there was light.
And so sometimes when you face a
problem, don't try to analyze the
problem. Don't try to figure out the
problem. Speak to the problem and say,
"Let there be light." Amen.
>> Just say it. You'll be amazed at what
happens. Let there be
>> light. Let there be light. Let there be
light. Let there be light. And I'm
speaking into somebody's situation right
now. Let there be light.
>> Amen. in Jesus name. But number two,
very quickly, words don't just create.
Words also authorize. Speak words that
authorize. These are the words that
uphold the kingdom of God. Mark 11 again
verse 23. Jesus is speaking to this tree
and he's saying after he spoke it, he's
now telling the disciples, "Truly I tell
you, if you anyone says to this
mountain, uh, that is a word of
authority, go
throw yourself into the sea and does not
doubt in their heart, but believes that
what they say will happen, it will be
done for them."
The Bible says this uh in the book of
Acts, we meet Peter and John going to
the temple to pray. Acts chapter 3:1,
the Bible says this. This is the story
of them putting this word of God into
into into the process. One day, Peter
and John were going up to the temple at
[clears throat] the time of prayer at
3:00 in the afternoon.
Now, a man who was lame from birth. Now,
remember, he's a man lame from from
birth. The guy has never walked. Now a
man who was lame from birth was being
carried to the temple gate called
beautiful where he was put every day to
beg from those going into the temple
courts. When he saw Peter and John about
to enter, he asked them for money which
was just very normal. Peter looked at
straight at him as did John. Then Peter
said, "Look at us."
So the man gave them his attention
expecting to get something from them.
Then Peter said, "Silver
or gold I do not have." I always like
Peter's honesty.
He didn't say, "Silver and gold we do
not have."
But they were there with John. So he
spoke about himself. Silver and gold,
>> I do not have. But what I do have, I
give you. That's now where the authority
comes. In the name of Jesus Christ of
Nazareth, do what?
>> Walk. The Bible says, taking him by the
right hand, he helped him up. And
instantly the man's feet and ankles
became strong. He jumped to his feet and
began to walk. Then he went with them
into the temple courts, walking and
jumping and praising God. When all the
people saw him walking and praising God,
they recognized him as the same man who
used to sit begging at the temple gate
called beautiful and they were filled
with wonder and amazement at what had
happened. Let me tell you that in this
month of February, people will be
amazed.
>> Amen.
>> At what God will have done for you.
>> I'm saying God is doing something for
you.
>> Somebody better receive that in Jesus
name.
>> Yes. People will look at you and say is
this the same person you know is this
the same person
and they say yeah it is the same person
but something has changed something is
different why Peter just took an
opportunity and spoke the word there's a
verse in Deuteronomy which is an
interesting um statement by by by God
and [clears throat] he's saying this in
Deuteronomy 30 verse 19 to20 because are
speaking is a choice.
God is giving you many choices. He says,
"This day I call the heavens
and the earth as witnesses against you
that I have set before you what?
>> Life and death,
blessings
and curses." And then he says, "Now
choose
>> life." He didn't say choose life or
death. He said, "Even though they are in
front of you, choose what?"
>> Life. So that you and your children may
live and that you may love the Lord your
God. Listen to his voice and hold fast
to him. For the Lord is your life, and
he will give you many years in the land
he swore to give to your fathers
Abraham, Isaac, and Jacob. choose you
this day. Did you know that through the
power of your tongue, you can actually
choose?
You can make choices.
Have you ever sometimes woken up and
say, "Today, I'm going to visit so and
so." Before you told anybody else, you
just said it, "Today I'm going to visit
so and so." Immediately everything
begins to align to what you did. What
you say? You begin to prepare yourself.
And then you meet somebody in the house.
You say, "By the way, today at 2:00 I'm
going to see so and so." Because you
have declared it. You have chosen to do
something.
Your tongue is powerful. Let me show you
this verse in James chapter 3 verse 4
and 5. The Bible says this about the
tongue.
It says, "Or take ships as an example.
Although they are so large and are
driven by strong winds, they are steered
by a very small rudder wherever the
pilot
wants to go." And then he says,
"Likewise, the tongue is a small part of
the body, but it makes great boasts.
Consider what a great forest.
It sets on fire by a small spark. Then
it says the tongue also is what? A fire.
A world of evil among the parts of the
body. It corrupts the whole body. Sets
the whole course of one's life on fire
and is itself set on fire by what?
>> Can you imagine?
Verse seven. All kinds of animals,
birds, reptiles, and sea creatures are
being tamed and have been tamed by
mankind. But no human being can tame the
tongue. It is a restless evil full of
deadly poison.
With a tongue we praise our Lord and
father, and with it we curse human
beings who have been made in God's
likeness. And then he says in verse 10,
out of the same mouth come praise and
cursing. My brothers and sisters, this
should not be because you have a choice.
You have a choice. Tell your neighbor,
you have a choice.
>> Take me back to um um Proverbs 18:21,
New King James Version, please. And it
says this, and I said it earlier for
you,
death
and life are in the power of the tongue,
and those who love it will eat its
fruit. This verse, Pastor Simon, I was
reading it, and in my mind, I just had
this thought. God is telling us,
this tongue we have can turn death to
life.
Death and life are in the power of the
tongue.
God does not want it to go the other way
around that we turn life
into death. He wants it to go the other
way. We turn death to life.
I was sharing this this thing that I
read the other day and there were these
two people relating with each other on
chat. They were chatting and this girl
is very young in her 20s, early 20s and
they're chatting and this guy is a
friend of hers and there were times they
had good conversation. They don't have
not never met but they have good
conversations. They're chatting. They
love each other all kinds of things. And
then one day the guy gets upset with the
girl and the guy sends a chat, a
statement saying,
"I'm so upset with you. I don't think
this world deserves you to be alive on
this earth.
That statement affected this girl that
same day she read that text. She
committed suicide.
The power of the tongue. But in this
instance, this person turned life
to death. God is saying, "Uh-uh.
Take dead things
and cause them to come to life. Make a
choice. Turn death to life."
I wrote some about 10 statements from
that statement. And I said, "Hey, I'm
going to put things in the right column.
There's this column, this column. This
column is about dead things. This column
is about things that are alive. And I'm
going now to choose. take take things
that are dead, make them alive because
you have that power. So this is what I
wrote down. I'm going to turn death to
life. I'm going to take turn curses
to blessings. Hallelujah. I'm going to
turn sickness
>> to health. I'm going to turn failure
>> to success. It is in your tongue. rudder
that R of a ship you can steer it you
can move it which whichever way you want
I'm going to turn baronness
baronness
>> yes so we are saying to any woman here
who is married but you have been barren
you will be fruitful
>> I'm saying you'll be fruitful
>> in fact you'll be so fruitful
that you will conceive and you'll have
twins in Jesus name.
Hello. Yes. God can we that that power
is in our tongue. Uh from stagnation
talk to me
>> to progress. Have you stagnated? We are
saying you'll progress.
>> Amen.
>> I'm saying you'll progress.
>> In Jesus name
>> from poverty.
to what?
>> Huh?
>> Oh, wealth.
>> I wrote something else.
>> From pro poverty to prosperity.
>> The same thing. Eh,
>> amen. You're going to prosper from
demotion
>> ah me to promotion in Jesus name. Ah,
you may have been retrenched. Ah, you
may have been laid off. But let me tell
you this. Keep declaring. Though I was
demoted, I'll be promoted.
>> Ah, I will be promoted.
>> And maybe these guys were just doing you
a favor by demoting you. Oh, they did
you a favor
>> because the next job you have, you'll be
the ones supplying for them
>> for your for for that boss who demoted
you. Look at your neighbor and tell your
neighbor, "Ah, I wish I was not that
boss."
Rather than you get demoted, you're
crying, "Oh, I was demoted. Oh, now my
life is over. Your life is not over.
Your life is not over. Your life is not
over. God is saying, "What can you put
on your tongue that I can change the
agenda?" Because it's what you say that
will shift things. God has already given
you a lot of things to say. um from
fear.
Uh
the answer to that will tell you about
those who went to the group of schools
and those who went to school in groups.
Hallelujah.
By the way, I'm one of those people who
went to school
>> in groups.
>> In groups.
Ah. So anyway,
fear
>> to courage. Hallelujah.
>> From complaining
>> to what?
>> To gratitude.
>> All right. God is good
>> and all of it is from where?
>> The tongue.
You can destroy your children just by
the tongue completely.
They try to rise, boom, try to rise,
boom, try to rise, boom.
I really thank God for my dad. Um
because one day he decided he was not
going to talk because I had really
failed.
Usually when I failed, ah that day
everybody will know in the estate that
something is wrong. I was I was very
bright and I'm still bright.
I'm saying I'm still bright
because in primary when we did three
subjects we did maths, English and
general paper. I passed them. I I in
maths I got an A, English A, general
paper A.
36 points. I I passed any pass. You know
there are some people who pass and there
others who pass.
I went to secondary school Jamuri High
School.
From one I met people who had also
passed seriously from other schools. So
we met all passers
a students all of us.
And in first term I really aced it. I
was doing well
in form two first time I became number
37 out of 38.
I knew that day my dad would kill me.
So I went home, put the report from
where he sits and waited for the hammer
to fall.
Do you know for a whole month of holiday
my dad never said anything?
Never meant a comment. Never even told
me where is the report form. He never
said anything. And pastor Simon that was
the most torturous holiday of my life
because every day I would pass the
sitting room. Ah as if I'm walking on
eggs passing the sitting room.
And then I would go from the kitchen to
the bedroom. I would pass the sitting
room and he's sitting there. I would
pass and he said nothing. Then I have to
find a way of getting out of the bedroom
to the kitchen. But I have to pass
for one month.
My dad said nothing.
Do you know when I went back to school
without being told
I worked so hard
that term from number 37 I became number
20 out of 38
most improved clap for me
and it's because my father did not kill
me destroy me by saying you are such a
fill in the blanks.
He never said it. And it was now up to
me knowing that I was right to come back
to my place. So I'm saying to somebody
today in Jesus name, watch what you say
to your children. They just failed an
exam. They're not failures. They just
failed.
>> You're not a failure. You just failed an
interview.
So don't don't close the curtains and
turn off your phone because of that
interview. It was just an interview.
Another one is coming
>> and you'll ace it in Jesus name.
>> Amen.
>> We authorize by the things we say. And
so your tongue tell your neighbor your
tongue.
>> Your tongue.
>> Say my tongue will be wise.
>> My tongue will be wise.
>> I will speak the right things.
>> I will authorize what is right. I will
>> and it will come to pass.
>> And it will come to pass.
>> Maybe for some of us, you are where you
are because of what you say today.
Change your speech.
You're a success. I'm saying you're a
success.
>> You're a success.
>> You're going places in Jesus name.
>> But let me tie this down by saying the
last thing. Words are given to us number
one to do what?
to create. Number two,
>> number three,
>> to bless,
>> to bless. So, let me read this verse and
then we shall pray for one another.
Numbers 6, these are verses we use every
Sunday here. Numbers 6:23-27.
God is giving the priests an
instruction. He says this, "Speak to
Aaron and his sons, saying, "This is the
way you shall bless the children of
Israel.
Say to them, "The Lord bless you and
keep you. The Lord make his face shine
upon you and be gracious to you."
Next, the Lord lift up his countenance
upon you and give you peace. Then God
says, "So shall
so they shall put my name on the
children of Israel and I will bless
them." So when we say those words, God
picks them and then God blesses us. Now
let me read this other verse. Numbers 23
verse 19. This is Balam who is trying to
curse God's people but God tells him
uh-uh I'm not changing my mind.
I read God is not a human that he should
lie nor a human being that he should
change his mind. Does he speak and then
not act? Does he promise and not
fulfill? And then Balam said this, I
have received a command to bless. He has
blessed and I cannot change it.
>> Let me read this in the New King James
Version because I want you to get this
lesson because you are going to be
blessing people and you're going to
bless yourself. You're going to bless
God. I read God is not a man that he
should lie nor a son of man that he
should repent. Has he said and will
I have received a command to bless. He
has blessed and I cannot reverse it.
Now come on, you give God a big hand.
So now listen to me because I'm a
priest.
Amen.
>> So
behold
me Ambrose now. Behold I have received a
command to bless.
>> Amen.
>> He has done what?
>> Bless
>> and I cannot do what?
>> Bless.
>> Thank you Jesus.
>> So I will whenever I command a blessing,
God then does what?
Who blesses
>> God?
>> God once he blesses
Ambrose cannot
>> reverse it. This is the kind of God we
serve.
>> So bless. Receive the blessings we
release to you because God will attach
them to you so that it's like a tracker.
No matter where you go, the blessing
does what?
>> Follows you. And there are things that
God has already released in your life to
bless and they're not going to happen in
December.
They're going not going to happen in
December. So let me read you this last
verse while you're standing on your
feet.
Hey, Pastor Simon, did you realize how
powerful my statement was?
I made all of us to stand.
Not by power.
I just spoke. Thank you, Jesus. Your
words are powerful. I just said, let's
stand
powerful.
But I like this one. This is this is a
verse I want somebody to carry home with
them. Ezekiel 12 26-28.
So while we're turning there, what three
things does the word of God do?
>> It creates
>> blesses. Look at this verse again. The
word of the Lord came to me saying, "Son
of man, look, the house of Paclands
is saying, the vision that he sees is
for many days from now, and he
prophesies of times far off.
Therefore said to the Planders, thus
says the Lord God, none of my words will
be postponed anymore.
Tell your neighbor, it's not in
December.
>> It's not in December.
>> It is in February.
>> In Jesus name.
>> Therefore say to them, thus says the
Lord God, none of my words will be
postponed anymore, but the word which I
speak will be done, says the Lord God.
I have put together a card which I pray
that you'll be able to get a copy in the
bookshop. It talks about a new open door
that uplifts and I have made about 12
statements. The first statement says
this, I declare that I am uplifted to a
new door of divine wealth. Number two, I
am uplifted to a new door of spiritual
walk. Number three, I am uplifted to a
new door of worldass impact. But I like
number six, I am uplifted to a new door
of unstoppable favor.
>> Amen.
>> That's your portion.
I'm saying that is your portion.
Look at your neighbor and tell your
neighbor, "Unstoppable favor is coming
my way."
>> Unstoppable favor is coming my way. Tell
the neighbor again, "Unstoppable favor
is coming my way."
>> Unstoppable favor is coming my way.
>> And tell them, "If you don't get your
favor,
>> I will take it for you.
>> In Jesus name.
>> In Jesus name."
>> So tell your neighbor, "My favor is
mine.
>> My favor is mine.
>> You are not taking it.
>> You're not taking it.
>> And that favor is unstoppable.
>> I'm going to great heights.
>> I'm going to great heights. this month
of February.
>> this month of February.
>> In Jesus name.
>> in Jesus name.
>> Now give God a big hand.
Of course this month like Pastor Simon
was saying is a month of relationships.
Of course there is Valentine coming up.
I'm saying there's Valentine's Day
coming up.
Um
and if you are not taken anywhere,
tell your neighbor, I still have
unstoppable favorable
>> in Jesus name.
>> That card is in a pack open door pack.
Get some copies. Share it with your
friends. Who knows that the seed you
plant in somebody's heart
>> will germinate to a great harvest. Amen.
>> Did you learn anything today?
>> Yes.
>> Are you going with something?
>> If I brought you here, would you tell me
what that something is?
>> Oh, I like that courage.
>> I like that confidence. May the Lord
accelerate you this month.
>> Amen.
>> May the Lord accelerate you this month.
>> In Jesus name.
>> Amen.
>> The door is open for you. So walk
through it. No weapon that is fashioned
against you will prosper.
>> Those of you who are planning to travel,
God will open doors for you
>> that no man can shut. You're traveling
in Jesus name. You're traveling in Jesus
name.
Some of you whose passports are stuck at
immigration, they're going to be
released in Jesus name.
>> God is good.
>> Yes. Some of you whose passports have
never been stamped, they'll be stamped
in Jesus name. Amen.
>> Some of you have been refused uh to go
in certain countries. Uh went for the
visa to go to the US. Um don't get
stuck. You're just stuck. I have to go
to the US. My friend, you can also go to
the UK.
Basim
is not very far.
Hello.
You want a stamp? Zimbabwe is not very
far.
>> The ambassador is here.
When Martha and I went to our honeymoon
asal.
Hello.
Guess where we went for our honeymoon?
>> Zimbabwe har. We had an amazing time.
Um, so let me tell you this. You're
going to travel.
>> Amen.
>> You're going to go beyond Kino.
in Jesus name.
But let me tell you this, you're also
going to fly out in Jesus name.
>> Receive that blessing in Jesus name.
>> Yes. Receive it. Huh?
Some of you have never traveled. Begin
to believe God. Begin to say it with
your mouth. I'm going to Dubai. Say it
by faith. I'm going to Dubai. You know,
you you're going to travel. You're going
to go with Emirates. You're going to go
with Qatar. You're going to go with KQ,
>> the Pride of Africa.
>> I'm saying you're going to places in
Jesus name.
>> Believe it. Decree it. Declare it. Those
seven prayer requests will happen to
you.
>> You're going places in Jesus name.
>> Your children are mighty in the land.
Husbands, you're going to get enough
money so that you can give some of it to
your wife.
Ah,
>> somebody better receive that.
>> Jesus name. Ah, wives, you also supposed
to share with your husbands.
Even though your money is your money,
but God is good.
Billa,
there's a miracle happening right now.
I sense that there are about
20 doors that are being opened
and have been opened.
Somebody better take them. Jesus name.
Some of those doors are financial.
>> Some of those doors are opportunities.
>> And they're not going to happen very
long from today.
Let's count seven days.
20 doors. Somebody's walking through
doors, doors, doors.
Those
doors were basically closed last week.
Ambrose has released a word.
They are being opened now.
>> Jesus name. Jesus name.
Receive it.
But this month also spend time to hear
God's word. Listen to his declarations.
And as you listen to his declarations,
begin to declare the same. declare the
same. God is a good God.
And so God wants you to be good. God
wants to expand your territory. Use your
words wisely.
And if you feel you're about to say
something bad, let it stay in your
heart. Let it stay there.
But if it is something good, say it. And
sometimes just wake up during the day
and say something good to everybody.
Give thanks.
So right now why don't you take two
three sentences say say something good
to somebody next to you tell them. I
will not ask what you told them but you
tell them.
Oh nice nice
mom.
Huh? She told you something. Okay.
Now I want to talk to those people who
did not open their mouth.
I want you now if is there somebody next
to you who did not open their mouth.
Did I hear? Yes.
Now let me give you one more chance.
Now for those who said it, you can
repeat. For those who didn't say, now
say it.
Don't look at me. Say it.
Huh? Yes.
Yes.
Wonderful.
Those in the pavilion. Now, I'm talking
to those in the pavilion. I hope you did
what I've just said. I'll find out.
God is good.
>> I really appreciate the talking hands. I
I could see them. when they were talking
with their
>> with their hands. They said something
good. And so let's let's appreciate our
talking hands.
Amen.
So practice practice this week. Uh
saying something good.
>> I'm so glad you came.
Father, as we pray,
what a blessing to be in God's house.
God, you are not a man that you should
lie. You're not a son of man that you
should change your mind. When you speak,
it is done. When you declare, it is
established.
And God like you said we bless
and then you bless
and I cannot reverse it.
So my God if I cannot reverse it I know
also you cannot reverse it because when
you say it is done and here for somebody
who is waiting for a promise to be
fulfilled I'm saying to you God will
come through for you.
>> God is blessing you this week.
You'll be amazed and astonished
that God will come to you so quickly
because acceleration is happening for
you now.
Father, thank you for hearing our
prayer. We give you all the glory and
all the praise. Because we have prayed
in Jesus name and God's people said
>> amen.
>> Come on, let's give God a big hand.
Amen.
So, we're going to say the blessing
together.
Uh, give me that verse number six where
it says, "The Lord bless you." Don't
say, "The Lord bless you." Say, "The
Lord bless me."
>> Okay? So, that's what you're going to
say. Every place, put your hand on your
chest. Here we go. One to go. The Lord
bless me and keep me. The Lord make his
face shine upon me and be gracious to
me. The Lord lift up his countenance
upon me and give me peace. Come on,
let's give God a big hand.
Amen.
Now look at your neighbor. Tell your
neighbor, surely goodness
>> Surely goodness
>> and mercy
>> shall follow you
>> all the days of your life. all the days
of your life.
>> And you
>> And you,
>> Yani, you
>> I'm talking to you.
>> You shall dwell
>> in God's favor.
>> In God's goodness,
>> in God's goodness,
>> in God's mercies,
>> in God's plenty,
>> in God's plenty.
>> And there's nothing the devil can do
about it.
>> There's nothing the devil can do about
it.
>> In Jesus name.
>> in Jesus name.
>> Amen.
And now may the grace of our Lord Jesus
Christ, the love of God, and the
fellowship of the Holy Spirit be with us
now and forever more. Amen. Shalom. Have
a great week.